MarketingKey	Purpose	Source	Purpose Description	Source Description
206	B	O	Breeding in captivity or artificial propagation	Out of date specimens
210	B	U	Breeding in captivity or artificial propagation	Unknown
214	E	A	Experiment	"Plants that are artificially propagated in accordance with Resolution Conf. 11.11 (Rev.CoP15), as well as parts and derivatives thereof, exported under the provisions of Article VII, paragraph 5, of the Convention (specimens of species included in Appendix I that have been propagated artificially for non-commercial purposes and specimens of species included in Appendices II and III)."
216	E	C	Experiment	"Animals bred in captivity in accordance with Resolution Conf. 10.16 (Rev.), as well as parts and derivatives thereof, exported under the provisions of Article VII, paragraph 5, of the Convention."
218	E	D	Experiment	"Appendix-I animals bred in captivity for commercial purposes in operations included in the Secretariat's Register, in accordance with Resolution Conf. 12.10 (Rev. CoP15), and Appendix-I plants artificially propagated for commercial purposes, as well as parts and derivatives thereof, exported under the provisions of Article VII, paragraph 4, of the Convention."
220	E	F	Experiment	"Animals born in captivity (F1 or subsequent generations) that do not fulfil the definition of 'bred in captivity' in Resolution Conf. 10.16 (Rev.), as well as parts and derivatives thereof."
222	E	I	Experiment	illegal specimens
224	E	O	Experiment	Out of date specimens
227	E	R	Experiment	"Ranched specimens: specimens of animals reared in a controlled environment, taken as eggs or juveniles from the wild, where they would otherwise have had a very low probability of surviving to adulthood.
228	E	U	Experiment	Unknown
230	E	W	Experiment	wild specimens.
232	G	A	Garden	"Plants that are artificially propagated in accordance with Resolution Conf. 11.11 (Rev.CoP15), as well as parts and derivatives thereof, exported under the provisions of Article VII, paragraph 5, of the Convention (specimens of species included in Appendix I that have been propagated artificially for non-commercial purposes and specimens of species included in Appendices II and III)."
234	G	D	Garden	"Appendix-I animals bred in captivity for commercial purposes in operations included in the Secretariat's Register, in accordance with Resolution Conf. 12.10 (Rev. CoP15), and Appendix-I plants artificially propagated for commercial purposes, as well as parts and derivatives thereof, exported under the provisions of Article VII, paragraph 4, of the Convention."
236	G	W	Garden	wild specimens.
240	H	I	Hunting trophy	illegal specimens
244	H	U	Hunting trophy	Unknown
246	H	W	Hunting trophy	wild specimens.
249	L	C	Law enforcement	"Animals bred in captivity in accordance with Resolution Conf. 10.16 (Rev.), as well as parts and derivatives thereof, exported under the provisions of Article VII, paragraph 5, of the Convention."
251	L	I	Law enforcement	illegal specimens
253	L	U	Law enforcement	Unknown
255	L	W	Law enforcement	wild specimens.
258	M	C	Medical	"Animals bred in captivity in accordance with Resolution Conf. 10.16 (Rev.), as well as parts and derivatives thereof, exported under the provisions of Article VII, paragraph 5, of the Convention."
260	M	D	Medical	"Appendix-I animals bred in captivity for commercial purposes in operations included in the Secretariat's Register, in accordance with Resolution Conf. 12.10 (Rev. CoP15), and Appendix-I plants artificially propagated for commercial purposes, as well as parts and derivatives thereof, exported under the provisions of Article VII, paragraph 4, of the Convention."
262	M	F	Medical	"Animals born in captivity (F1 or subsequent generations) that do not fulfil the definition of 'bred in captivity' in Resolution Conf. 10.16 (Rev.), as well as parts and derivatives thereof."
264	M	I	Medical	illegal specimens
266	M	O	Medical	Out of date specimens
268	M	U	Medical	Unknown
270	M	W	Medical	wild specimens.
275	N	I	Reintroduction or introduction into the wild	illegal specimens
279	N	W	Reintroduction or introduction into the wild	wild specimens.
285	P	I	Personal	illegal specimens
290	P	U	Personal	Unknown
292	P	W	Personal	wild specimens.
299	Q	I	Circus or travelling exhibition	illegal specimens
301	Q	O	Circus or travelling exhibition	Out of date specimens
304	Q	U	Circus or travelling exhibition	Unknown
306	Q	W	Circus or travelling exhibition	wild specimens.
310	S	C	Science Research	"Animals bred in captivity in accordance with Resolution Conf. 10.16 (Rev.), as well as parts and derivatives thereof, exported under the provisions of Article VII, paragraph 5, of the Convention."
312	S	D	Science Research	"Appendix-I animals bred in captivity for commercial purposes in operations included in the Secretariat's Register, in accordance with Resolution Conf. 12.10 (Rev. CoP15), and Appendix-I plants artificially propagated for commercial purposes, as well as parts and derivatives thereof, exported under the provisions of Article VII, paragraph 4, of the Convention."
314	S	F	Science Research	"Animals born in captivity (F1 or subsequent generations) that do not fulfil the definition of 'bred in captivity' in Resolution Conf. 10.16 (Rev.), as well as parts and derivatives thereof."
316	S	I	Science Research	illegal specimens
318	S	O	Science Research	Out of date specimens
320	S	R	Science Research	"Ranched specimens: specimens of animals reared in a controlled environment, taken as eggs or juveniles from the wild, where they would otherwise have had a very low probability of surviving to adulthood.
322	S	U	Science Research	Unknown
324	S	W	Science Research	wild specimens.
326	S	X	Science Research	Specimens taken in the marine environment not under the jurisdiction of any State.
329	T	A	Training	"Plants that are artificially propagated in accordance with Resolution Conf. 11.11 (Rev.CoP15), as well as parts and derivatives thereof, exported under the provisions of Article VII, paragraph 5, of the Convention (specimens of species included in Appendix I that have been propagated artificially for non-commercial purposes and specimens of species included in Appendices II and III)."
331	T	C	Training	"Animals bred in captivity in accordance with Resolution Conf. 10.16 (Rev.), as well as parts and derivatives thereof, exported under the provisions of Article VII, paragraph 5, of the Convention."
333	T	D	Training	"Appendix-I animals bred in captivity for commercial purposes in operations included in the Secretariat's Register, in accordance with Resolution Conf. 12.10 (Rev. CoP15), and Appendix-I plants artificially propagated for commercial purposes, as well as parts and derivatives thereof, exported under the provisions of Article VII, paragraph 4, of the Convention."
335	T	F	Training	"Animals born in captivity (F1 or subsequent generations) that do not fulfil the definition of 'bred in captivity' in Resolution Conf. 10.16 (Rev.), as well as parts and derivatives thereof."
337	T	I	Training	illegal specimens
340	T	O	Training	Out of date specimens
341	T	R	Training	"Ranched specimens: specimens of animals reared in a controlled environment, taken as eggs or juveniles from the wild, where they would otherwise have had a very low probability of surviving to adulthood.
343	T	U	Training	Unknown
345	T	W	Training	wild specimens.
347	T	X	Training	Specimens taken in the marine environment not under the jurisdiction of any State.
349	T		Training	
354	Z	I	Zoo	illegal specimens
356	Z	O	Zoo	Out of date specimens
359	Z	U	Zoo	Unknown
361	Z	W	Zoo	wild specimens.
367		O		Out of date specimens
370		W		wild specimens.
201	B	A	Breeding in captivity or artificial propagation	"Plants that are artificially propagated in accordance with Resolution Conf. 11.11 (Rev.CoP15), as well as parts and derivatives thereof, exported under the provisions of Article VII, paragraph 5, of the Convention (specimens of species included in Appendix I that have been propagated artificially for non-commercial purposes and specimens of species included in Appendices II and III)."
202	B	C	Breeding in captivity or artificial propagation	"Animals bred in captivity in accordance with Resolution Conf. 10.16 (Rev.), as well as parts and derivatives thereof, exported under the provisions of Article VII, paragraph 5, of the Convention."
203	B	D	Breeding in captivity or artificial propagation	"Appendix-I animals bred in captivity for commercial purposes in operations included in the Secretariat's Register, in accordance with Resolution Conf. 12.10 (Rev. CoP15), and Appendix-I plants artificially propagated for commercial purposes, as well as parts and derivatives thereof, exported under the provisions of Article VII, paragraph 4, of the Convention."
204	B	F	Breeding in captivity or artificial propagation	"Animals born in captivity (F1 or subsequent generations) that do not fulfil the definition of 'bred in captivity' in Resolution Conf. 10.16 (Rev.), as well as parts and derivatives thereof."
205	B	I	Breeding in captivity or artificial propagation	Confiscated or seized specimens
206	B	O	Breeding in captivity or artificial propagation	Pre-Convention specimens
208	B	R	Breeding in captivity or artificial propagation	"Ranched specimens: specimens of animals reared in a controlled environment, taken as eggs or juveniles from the wild, where they would otherwise have had a very low probability of surviving to adulthood.
209	B	U	Breeding in captivity or artificial propagation	Source unknown.
210	B	W	Breeding in captivity or artificial propagation	Specimens taken from the wild.
213	B		Breeding in captivity or artificial propagation	
214	E	A	Educational	"Plants that are artificially propagated in accordance with Resolution Conf. 11.11 (Rev.CoP15), as well as parts and derivatives thereof, exported under the provisions of Article VII, paragraph 5, of the Convention (specimens of species included in Appendix I that have been propagated artificially for non-commercial purposes and specimens of species included in Appendices II and III)."
216	E	C	Educational	"Animals bred in captivity in accordance with Resolution Conf. 10.16 (Rev.), as well as parts and derivatives thereof, exported under the provisions of Article VII, paragraph 5, of the Convention."
218	E	D	Educational	"Appendix-I animals bred in captivity for commercial purposes in operations included in the Secretariat's Register, in accordance with Resolution Conf. 12.10 (Rev. CoP15), and Appendix-I plants artificially propagated for commercial purposes, as well as parts and derivatives thereof, exported under the provisions of Article VII, paragraph 4, of the Convention."
220	E	F	Educational	"Animals born in captivity (F1 or subsequent generations) that do not fulfil the definition of 'bred in captivity' in Resolution Conf. 10.16 (Rev.), as well as parts and derivatives thereof."
222	E	I	Educational	Confiscated or seized specimens
224	E	O	Educational	Pre-Convention specimens
227	E	R	Educational	"Ranched specimens: specimens of animals reared in a controlled environment, taken as eggs or juveniles from the wild, where they would otherwise have had a very low probability of surviving to adulthood.
228	E	U	Educational	Source unknown.
230	E	W	Educational	Specimens taken from the wild.
232	G	A	Botanical garden	"Plants that are artificially propagated in accordance with Resolution Conf. 11.11 (Rev.CoP15), as well as parts and derivatives thereof, exported under the provisions of Article VII, paragraph 5, of the Convention (specimens of species included in Appendix I that have been propagated artificially for non-commercial purposes and specimens of species included in Appendices II and III)."
234	G	D	Botanical garden	"Appendix-I animals bred in captivity for commercial purposes in operations included in the Secretariat's Register, in accordance with Resolution Conf. 12.10 (Rev. CoP15), and Appendix-I plants artificially propagated for commercial purposes, as well as parts and derivatives thereof, exported under the provisions of Article VII, paragraph 4, of the Convention."
236	G	W	Botanical garden	Specimens taken from the wild.
238	H	C	Hunting trophy	"Animals bred in captivity in accordance with Resolution Conf. 10.16 (Rev.), as well as parts and derivatives thereof, exported under the provisions of Article VII, paragraph 5, of the Convention."
239	H	F	Hunting trophy	"Animals born in captivity (F1 or subsequent generations) that do not fulfil the definition of 'bred in captivity' in Resolution Conf. 10.16 (Rev.), as well as parts and derivatives thereof."
240	H	I	Hunting trophy	Confiscated or seized specimens
242	H	O	Hunting trophy	Pre-Convention specimens
243	H	R	Hunting trophy	"Ranched specimens: specimens of animals reared in a controlled environment, taken as eggs or juveniles from the wild, where they would otherwise have had a very low probability of surviving to adulthood.
244	H	U	Hunting trophy	Source unknown.
246	H	W	Hunting trophy	Specimens taken from the wild.
248	H		Hunting trophy	
249	L	C	Law enforcement / judicial / forensic	"Animals bred in captivity in accordance with Resolution Conf. 10.16 (Rev.), as well as parts and derivatives thereof, exported under the provisions of Article VII, paragraph 5, of the Convention."
251	L	I	Law enforcement / judicial / forensic	Confiscated or seized specimens
253	L	U	Law enforcement / judicial / forensic	Source unknown.
255	L	W	Law enforcement / judicial / forensic	Specimens taken from the wild.
257	L		Law enforcement	
258	M	C	Medical (including biomedical research)	"Animals bred in captivity in accordance with Resolution Conf. 10.16 (Rev.), as well as parts and derivatives thereof, exported under the provisions of Article VII, paragraph 5, of the Convention."
260	M	D	Medical (including biomedical research)	"Appendix-I animals bred in captivity for commercial purposes in operations included in the Secretariat's Register, in accordance with Resolution Conf. 12.10 (Rev. CoP15), and Appendix-I plants artificially propagated for commercial purposes, as well as parts and derivatives thereof, exported under the provisions of Article VII, paragraph 4, of the Convention."
262	M	F	Medical (including biomedical research)	"Animals born in captivity (F1 or subsequent generations) that do not fulfil the definition of 'bred in captivity' in Resolution Conf. 10.16 (Rev.), as well as parts and derivatives thereof."
264	M	I	Medical (including biomedical research)	Confiscated or seized specimens
266	M	O	Medical (including biomedical research)	Pre-Convention specimens
268	M	U	Medical (including biomedical research)	Source unknown.
270	M	W	Medical (including biomedical research)	Specimens taken from the wild.
272	M		Medical (including biomedical research)	
273	N	C	Reintroduction or introduction into the wild	"Animals bred in captivity in accordance with Resolution Conf. 10.16 (Rev.), as well as parts and derivatives thereof, exported under the provisions of Article VII, paragraph 5, of the Convention."
274	N	F	Reintroduction or introduction into the wild	"Animals born in captivity (F1 or subsequent generations) that do not fulfil the definition of 'bred in captivity' in Resolution Conf. 10.16 (Rev.), as well as parts and derivatives thereof."
275	N	I	Reintroduction or introduction into the wild	Confiscated or seized specimens
277	N	R	Reintroduction or introduction into the wild	"Ranched specimens: specimens of animals reared in a controlled environment, taken as eggs or juveniles from the wild, where they would otherwise have had a very low probability of surviving to adulthood.
278	N	U	Reintroduction or introduction into the wild	Unknown
279	N	W	Reintroduction or introduction into the wild	Specimens taken from the wild.
281	P	A	Personal	"Plants that are artificially propagated in accordance with Resolution Conf. 11.11 (Rev.CoP15), as well as parts and derivatives thereof, exported under the provisions of Article VII, paragraph 5, of the Convention (specimens of species included in Appendix I that have been propagated artificially for non-commercial purposes and specimens of species included in Appendices II and III)."
282	P	C	Personal	"Animals bred in captivity in accordance with Resolution Conf. 10.16 (Rev.), as well as parts and derivatives thereof, exported under the provisions of Article VII, paragraph 5, of the Convention."
283	P	D	Personal	"Appendix-I animals bred in captivity for commercial purposes in operations included in the Secretariat's Register, in accordance with Resolution Conf. 12.10 (Rev. CoP15), and Appendix-I plants artificially propagated for commercial purposes, as well as parts and derivatives thereof, exported under the provisions of Article VII, paragraph 4, of the Convention."
284	P	F	Personal	"Animals born in captivity (F1 or subsequent generations) that do not fulfil the definition of 'bred in captivity' in Resolution Conf. 10.16 (Rev.), as well as parts and derivatives thereof."
285	P	I	Personal	Confiscated or seized specimens
287	P	O	Personal	Pre-Convention specimens
289	P	R	Personal	"Ranched specimens: specimens of animals reared in a controlled environment, taken as eggs or juveniles from the wild, where they would otherwise have had a very low probability of surviving to adulthood.
290	P	U	Personal	Source unknown.
292	P	W	Personal	Specimens taken from the wild.
294	P		Personal	
295	Q	A	Circus or travelling exhibition	"Plants that are artificially propagated in accordance with Resolution Conf. 11.11 (Rev.CoP15), as well as parts and derivatives thereof, exported under the provisions of Article VII, paragraph 5, of the Convention (specimens of species included in Appendix I that have been propagated artificially for non-commercial purposes and specimens of species included in Appendices II and III)."
296	Q	C	Circus or travelling exhibition	"Animals bred in captivity in accordance with Resolution Conf. 10.16 (Rev.), as well as parts and derivatives thereof, exported under the provisions of Article VII, paragraph 5, of the Convention."
297	Q	D	Circus or travelling exhibition	"Appendix-I animals bred in captivity for commercial purposes in operations included in the Secretariat's Register, in accordance with Resolution Conf. 12.10 (Rev. CoP15), and Appendix-I plants artificially propagated for commercial purposes, as well as parts and derivatives thereof, exported under the provisions of Article VII, paragraph 4, of the Convention."
298	Q	F	Circus or travelling exhibition	"Animals born in captivity (F1 or subsequent generations) that do not fulfil the definition of 'bred in captivity' in Resolution Conf. 10.16 (Rev.), as well as parts and derivatives thereof."
299	Q	I	Circus or travelling exhibition	Confiscated or seized specimens
301	Q	O	Circus or travelling exhibition	Pre-Convention specimens
303	Q	R	Circus or travelling exhibition	"Ranched specimens: specimens of animals reared in a controlled environment, taken as eggs or juveniles from the wild, where they would otherwise have had a very low probability of surviving to adulthood.
304	Q	U	Circus or travelling exhibition	Source unknown.
306	Q	W	Circus or travelling exhibition	Specimens taken from the wild.
308	S	A	Science Research	"Plants that are artificially propagated in accordance with Resolution Conf. 11.11 (Rev.CoP15), as well as parts and derivatives thereof, exported under the provisions of Article VII, paragraph 5, of the Convention (specimens of species included in Appendix I that have been propagated artificially for non-commercial purposes and specimens of species included in Appendices II and III)."
309	S	A	Scientific	"Plants that are artificially propagated in accordance with Resolution Conf. 11.11 (Rev.CoP15), as well as parts and derivatives thereof, exported under the provisions of Article VII, paragraph 5, of the Convention (specimens of species included in Appendix I that have been propagated artificially for non-commercial purposes and specimens of species included in Appendices II and III)."
310	S	C	Scientific	"Animals bred in captivity in accordance with Resolution Conf. 10.16 (Rev.), as well as parts and derivatives thereof, exported under the provisions of Article VII, paragraph 5, of the Convention."
312	S	D	Scientific	"Appendix-I animals bred in captivity for commercial purposes in operations included in the Secretariat's Register, in accordance with Resolution Conf. 12.10 (Rev. CoP15), and Appendix-I plants artificially propagated for commercial purposes, as well as parts and derivatives thereof, exported under the provisions of Article VII, paragraph 4, of the Convention."
314	S	F	Scientific	"Animals born in captivity (F1 or subsequent generations) that do not fulfil the definition of 'bred in captivity' in Resolution Conf. 10.16 (Rev.), as well as parts and derivatives thereof."
316	S	I	Scientific	Confiscated or seized specimens
318	S	O	Scientific	Pre-Convention specimens
320	S	R	Scientific	"Ranched specimens: specimens of animals reared in a controlled environment, taken as eggs or juveniles from the wild, where they would otherwise have had a very low probability of surviving to adulthood.
322	S	U	Scientific	Source unknown.
324	S	W	Scientific	Specimens taken from the wild.
326	S	X	Scientific	Specimens taken in the marine environment not under the jurisdiction of any State.
328	S		Scientific	
329	T	A	Commercial	"Plants that are artificially propagated in accordance with Resolution Conf. 11.11 (Rev.CoP15), as well as parts and derivatives thereof, exported under the provisions of Article VII, paragraph 5, of the Convention (specimens of species included in Appendix I that have been propagated artificially for non-commercial purposes and specimens of species included in Appendices II and III)."
331	T	C	Commercial	"Animals bred in captivity in accordance with Resolution Conf. 10.16 (Rev.), as well as parts and derivatives thereof, exported under the provisions of Article VII, paragraph 5, of the Convention."
333	T	D	Commercial	"Appendix-I animals bred in captivity for commercial purposes in operations included in the Secretariat's Register, in accordance with Resolution Conf. 12.10 (Rev. CoP15), and Appendix-I plants artificially propagated for commercial purposes, as well as parts and derivatives thereof, exported under the provisions of Article VII, paragraph 4, of the Convention."
335	T	F	Commercial	"Animals born in captivity (F1 or subsequent generations) that do not fulfil the definition of 'bred in captivity' in Resolution Conf. 10.16 (Rev.), as well as parts and derivatives thereof."
337	T	I	Commercial	Confiscated or seized specimens
340	T	O	Commercial	Pre-Convention specimens
341	T	R	Commercial	"Ranched specimens: specimens of animals reared in a controlled environment, taken as eggs or juveniles from the wild, where they would otherwise have had a very low probability of surviving to adulthood.
343	T	U	Commercial	Source unknown.
345	T	W	Commercial	Specimens taken from the wild.
347	T	X	Commercial	Specimens taken in the marine environment not under the jurisdiction of any State.
349	T		Commercial	
351	Z	C	Zoo	"Animals bred in captivity in accordance with Resolution Conf. 10.16 (Rev.), as well as parts and derivatives thereof, exported under the provisions of Article VII, paragraph 5, of the Convention."
352	Z	D	Zoo	"Appendix-I animals bred in captivity for commercial purposes in operations included in the Secretariat's Register, in accordance with Resolution Conf. 12.10 (Rev. CoP15), and Appendix-I plants artificially propagated for commercial purposes, as well as parts and derivatives thereof, exported under the provisions of Article VII, paragraph 4, of the Convention."
353	Z	F	Zoo	"Animals born in captivity (F1 or subsequent generations) that do not fulfil the definition of 'bred in captivity' in Resolution Conf. 10.16 (Rev.), as well as parts and derivatives thereof."
354	Z	I	Zoo	Confiscated or seized specimens
356	Z	O	Zoo	Pre-Convention specimens
358	Z	R	Zoo	"Ranched specimens: specimens of animals reared in a controlled environment, taken as eggs or juveniles from the wild, where they would otherwise have had a very low probability of surviving to adulthood.
359	Z	U	Zoo	Source unknown.
361	Z	W	Zoo	Specimens taken from the wild.
363	Z		Zoo	
364		A		"Plants that are artificially propagated in accordance with Resolution Conf. 11.11 (Rev.CoP15), as well as parts and derivatives thereof, exported under the provisions of Article VII, paragraph 5, of the Convention (specimens of species included in Appendix I that have been propagated artificially for non-commercial purposes and specimens of species included in Appendices II and III)."
365		C		"Animals bred in captivity in accordance with Resolution Conf. 10.16 (Rev.), as well as parts and derivatives thereof, exported under the provisions of Article VII, paragraph 5, of the Convention."
366		F		"Animals born in captivity (F1 or subsequent generations) that do not fulfil the definition of 'bred in captivity' in Resolution Conf. 10.16 (Rev.), as well as parts and derivatives thereof."
367		O		Pre-Convention specimens
369		U		Source unknown.
370		W		Specimens taken from the wild.
372				
373	P	O	Personal	Out of date specimens